Guide to the Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Numerical, 401-500, Series XVIII
  - No. 478: Bassett, J. Walter and Evangeline Cunningham Bassett
    - Correspondence
      Letters addressed to J. Walter Bassett, primarily from Evangeline Cunningham Bassett.
      - 1896-1900 September (Box 104, Folder 1-11)
      - 1900 October-1901 July (Box 105, Folder 1-10)
      - 1901 August-1903 Dec, 1910 June (Box 106, Folder 1-12)
    - Pocket diaries, 1924, 1927-1929 (Box 106, Folder 13)
    - Photograph of Elizabeth Cunningham (later Mrs. J. Walter Bassett), late 1800s (Box 106, Folder 14)
  - No. 479: Maria Bruss diary, 1930s-1945
    The diary documents Bruss's work and family life in the Soviet Union during the 1930s and 1940s; the Soviet home front during World War II; women in the Soviet Union; denunciation in the Soviet Union, and her family's experiences during the Russian civil war and collectivization. Included is a typewritten version of the diary and a newspaper account documenting the discovery of the diary, both in Russian.
    - Original diary, 1930s-1945 (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper article regarding the discovery of the diary (Box 107, Folder 2)
    - Transcription of the diary, Undated (Box 107, Folder 3)
  - No. 480: Photograph of Sigmund Freud, undated (Box 107, Folder 4)
  - No. 481: Material relating to Algernon Joseph Lamb, undated (Box 107, Folder 5)
    Includes a newspaper clipping about Lamb's military service for the British army in World War I; some pencil sketches of aniamls and heraldic images; and a typescript description of titled Boating on the Nidd Goldsborough to York in a Canoe.
  - No. 482: Manuscript by an unidentified author on Naples, opera music, Gioachino Rossini, the Royal San Carlo Opera House, and an innkeeper named Beltrame (Box 107, Folder 6)
  - No. 483: Two postcards with images of the Azores, including one captioned "Antiga entrada de Ponta Delgada - São Miguel-Açores" and one captioned "costumes - Fayal (Açores)" (Box 107, Folder 7)
  - No. 484: Card with a cartoon on the front of a removals van, captioned "As a short cut from Earls Court to Twickenham, Bert, this is ridiculous!", circa 1970 (Box 107, Folder 8)
    Contains a note from Arthur Lovegrove and a photograph of two unidentified people, possibly including Lovegrove.
- Miscellaneous Manuscripts: Oversize
  - Adams, Daniel Lucius, 1862 (Box 99C)
  - Allen, Henry Trowbridge, undated (Box 99C)
  - American Missionary Association, 1865 (Box 99C)
  - American Museum of Natural History, 1925 (Box 99C)
  - Amherst College, 1848 (Box 99C)
  - Antimasonic Convention, Philadelphia, 1830 (Box 99C)
  - Astronomical charts, 1806, 1812 (Box 99C)
  - Banneker, Benjamin, 1791 (Box 99C)
  - Basseterre, Island of St. Christopher. Notary Public, 1800 (Box 99C)
  - Blackwell, Samuel, 1810 (Box 99C)
  - Bombay, India. Tramways, undated (Box 99C)
  - Bradley, Oliver S., 1857 (Box 99C)
  - Breckenridge-Webber Collection, 1783 (Box 99C)
  - Brown, Horace, 1755-1756 (Box 99C)
  - Büchler, Joseph and Anne Marie, 1857-1860 (Box 99C)
  - Bulkeley, William E., 1834 (Box 99C)
  - Canterbury (Province), 1763 (Box 99D)
  - Catholic Church, 1523 (Box 99D)
  - Central America
    - Bonilla, Antonio, 1790 (Box 99D)
    - Navarro, Luis Diez, 1745 (Box 99D)
    - Prosper, Felix, 1744 (Box 99D)
  - Clarke, Samuel, 1704 (Box 99D)
  - Coffin, Thomas Aston, 1868 (Box 99D)
  - Davenport, [Darius?], 1842 (Box 99D)
  - Dunk, Walter, 1899 (Box 99D)
  - Egypt. Intendance Générale Sanitaire, 1872 (Box 99D)
  - France. Legation, Great Britain, 1822 (Box 99E)
  - Frissell, Algernon Sydney, 1925 (Box 99E)
  - Glenn, John C., Collection, Circa 1828 (Box 99E)
  - Göttingen. Universität, 1820 (Box 99E)
  - Hamilton, Alexander, 1826 (Box 99E)
  - Harvard College, undated (Box 99E)
  - Hill, Edwin Allston, 1835, 1863-1913 (Box 99E)
  - Hoffman, Herman, 1792 (Box 99E)
  - Hungarian MSS, 1798, [1827?], 1843 (Box 99E)
  - Kennedy, John Fitzgerald, 1963 (Box 99F)
  - Kimberly, Dennis, undated (Box 99F)
  - Lee, Arthur T., 1858 (Box 99F)
  - Leipzig. Universität, 1828 (Box 99F)
  - Lewis, Edmund, 1724/1725 (Box 99F)
  - Lincoln, Abraham, 1863-1864, undated (Box 99F)
  - McCalley, James, 1795 (Box 99F)
  - McEvers, Charles, 1789 (Box 99F)
  - McMurdo, Thomas, 1848 (Box 99F)
  - Madison, James, 1809 (Box 99F)
  - Marbois, François de Barbé, marquis de, 1802 (Box 99F)
  - Massachusetts (Colony). Governor (William Shirley), 1744, 1761 (Box 99F)
  - Massachusetts Infantry, 11th regiment, 1780 (Box 99F)
  - Medical College of Pennsylvania, 1849 (Box 99F)
  - Mexico: Retz, Francisco, 1736 (Box 99F)
  - Middleton, James, 1873 (Box 99F)
  - Millnes, Joshua, 1691 (Box 99F)
  - Monroe, James, 1824 (Box 99F)
  - Morris, Angela J., 1893 (Box 99F)
  - Munich. Universität, 1896 (Box 99F)
  - New Jersey. Convention, 1787 (Box 99B)
  - New Jersey. Governor (George C. Ludlow), Circa 1860 (Box 99B)
  - New Jersey. Governor (Morgan D. Larson), 1930 (Box 99B)
  - New York (State). Governor (George Clinton), 1790 (Box 99B)
  - New York (State). Governor (Charles Evans Hughes), 1907-1908 (Box 99B)
  - Patterson Family Collection, 1787 (Box 99B)
  - Peck, Henry Brandagee, 1862 (Box 99B)
  - Penn, William, family, 1681-l733 (Box 99A)
  - Pomerania, 1696 (Box 99B)
  - Puerto Rico. Treasurer, 1876 (Box 99B)
  - Pynchon, William, family, 1599, 1603 (Box 99B)
  - Reims. Notre-Dame (Cathedral), undated (Box 99G)
  - Riley, Isaac, 1810 (Box 99G)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, 1963 (Box 99G)
  - Root, Henry Ide, 1899 (Box 99G)
  - Ruck, John, 1732/1733-1753 (Box 99G)
  - Savage, Arthur, 1711 (Box 99G)
  - Slevin, Gerard, 1958 (Box 99G)
  - Spear, Thomas G., undated (Box 99G)
  - Starr family, 1835 (Box 99G)
  - Stebbins, Laura (Allen), 1798 (Box 99G)
  - Stocking, Joseph, 1745 (Box 99G)
  - Stoddard family, 1716 (Box 99G)
  - Storrs family, 1816-1817 (Box 99G)
  - Tammany Society, 1810 (Box 100G)
  - Truchsess von Wurtzach, graf von, 1785 (Box 100G)
  - U.S. Constitution, undated (Box 100G)
  - U.S. Declaration of Independence, undated (Box 100G)
  - U.S. Department of State, 1850, 1852 (Box 100G)
  - U.S. General Land Office, 1819-1873 (Box 100)
  - U.S. Patent Office, 1858 (Box 100G)
  - Vanderheyden, Jacob D., 1794 (Box 100F)
  - Virginia. Governor (Patrick Henry), 1786 (Box 100F)
  - Ward, Frederick Townsend, 1862, undated (Box 100)
    See: Frederick Townsend Ward Pgs (1666)
  - Ware, Uriah, 1803 (Box 100F)
  - Webb, Nathaniel, 1772 (Box 100F)
  - Webster, Daniel, 1821 (Box 100G)
  - Welch, Deming N., 1868 (Box 100F)
  - West, George and Triphena, 1810 (Box 100F)
  - Willson, Elinor, 1791 (Box 100F)
  - Yale Business College, New Haven, 1881 (Box 100F)
  - York Collegiate Institute, York, Pennsylvania, 1919 (Box 100)
  - No. 3: Allis, Elisha, and Sarah Cutter, 1765 (Box 100H)
  - No. 10: Deane, Silas, 1776-1836 (Box 100)
  - No. 21: Gibbs, Abraham, 1806 (Box 100H)
  - No. 35: Rigail, L. A., 1819, 1827 (Box 100H)
  - No. 73: Fowler, James, family, 1859, undated (Box 100)
  - No. 156: Dixon, Alan C., Memorial Collection, 1718, 1796, 1803 (Box 100H)
  - No. 185: Gerry, Elbridge, 1812 (Box 100H)
  - No. 205: Longenecker, David, 1851 (Box 100H)
  - No. 248: Lang, Louis, 1872 (Box 100A)
  - No. 253: Pius VII, pope, 1802 (Box 100A)
  - No. 261: Mifflin, Thomas, 1796 (Box 100A)
  - No. 299: Tener, Hugh W., 1853-1862 (Box 100A)
  - No. 300: King, John Alsop, 1857 (Box 100A)
  - No. 304: Rogers, James Gamble, Jr., Circa 1942-1943 (Box 100A)
  - No. 308: Ross, David, 1772-1804 (Box 100A)
  - No. 310: Kissam, Daniel Whitehead, 1791 (Box 100A)
  - No. 346: Customs documents, 1799, 1826 (Box 100A)
  - No. 374: McDannel, Thomas Humes, 1919 (Box 100I)
  - No. 378: Pennsylvania. Governor (James A. Beaver), 1887 (Box 100I)
  - No. 379: Doran, James, plaintiff, 1765-1767 (Box 100I)
  - No. 387: The Zealandia "Star", undated (Box 100I)
  - No. 392: Sprague Family Papers, 1771-1831 (Box 100I)
  - No. 425: Furman, John, 1712 (Box 100I)
  - No. 426: Oneida County, N.Y., 1801-1802 (Box 100I)
  - No. 457: Yiddish theater in Poland, 1986, undated (Box 100E)
  - No. 458: Manifestos of the Old Yishuv in Jerusalem, Circa 1910- 1941 (Box 100J)
  - No. 459: Cost of living charts of Richmond T. and Caroline M. Roberts of Hamden, CT, 1927,1957, 1959, 1963-1966; Poole family genealogy (Box 100D)
  - No. 465: "Genealogy of the Family of Symington in Scotland" [printed chart tracing the family from pre-1300s; included is Symington family in New Jersey, U.S.A.], undated (Box 100C)
  - No. 466: Color photograph of the "Tribute in Light" memorial at the World Trade Center site, New York City, 2002 March 11 (Box 100B)
  - No. 475: Three Italian travel posters, 1923 (Box 101)
    Travel posters for Napoli, Roma and Tivoli - Villa d'este.
  - No. 476: Photograph of "Officers of the American Historical Association" with original backing and negative, 1889 December 30 (Box 102, Folder 1)
    Individuals depicted are William F. Poole, LLD of Chicago; Justin Winsor, LLD of Harvard University; Charles Kendall Adams, LLD, president of Cornell University; Professor Herbert B. Adams, PhD of Johns Hopkins University; Honorable George Bancroft, LLD; Honarable John Jay of New York; Clarence Winthrop Bowen, PhD; and Honorable Andrew D. White.
  - No. 477: Photograph of Sun Yat-sen (commonly known as the "father of Modern China") and his letter to Francis W. Damon, president of the Mid-Pacific Institute, 1912 February 8 (Box 103)
  - Poster of "cincuentario de la guerra española, homenaje a las brigades internacionales, 16, 17, 18 y 19 de octubre 1986--Madrid" [50th Anniversary of the Spanish Civil War, Tribute to the International Brigades, October 16, 17, 18, 19, 1986] (Box 104)